<rules>
    <rule>
        <key>CustomRuleTemplate</key>
        <cardinality>MULTIPLE</cardinality>
        <name><![CDATA[Template for custom Custom rules]]></name>
        <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Follow these steps to make your custom Custom rules available in SonarQube:
</p>

<ol>
  <ol>
    <li>Create a new rule in SonarQube by "copying" this rule template and specify the <code>CheckId</code> of your custom rule, a title, a description, and a default severity.</li>
    <li>Enable the newly created rule in your quality profile</li>
  </ol>
  <li>Relaunch an analysis on your projects, et voilà, your custom rules are executed!</li>
</ol>
]]></description>
        <severity>INFO</severity>
    </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>F001</key>
    <name>(CR) detected in isolation</name>
    <description>
      As a commonly accepted practice, line breaks are denoted by a
      single '\n' (LF) character or by two characters "\r\n" (CRLF).
      A single appearance of '\r' (CR) is discouraged.
    </description>
    <internalKey>F001</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>F002</key>
    <name>File names should be well formed</name>
    <description>
      The source file names should be well-formed in the sense of
      their allowed maximum length and directory depth. Directory and
      file names should start with alphabetic character or
      underscore. In addition, directory names should not contain dots
      and file names can have only one dot.
    </description>
    <internalKey>F002</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>L001</key>
    <name>Avoid trailing whitespace</name>
    <description>
      Trailing whitespace is any whitespace character (space or tab)
      that is placed at the end of the source line, after other
      characters or alone. The presence of trailing whitespace
      artificially influences some source code metrics and is
      therefore discouraged. As a special case, the trailing
      whitespace in the otherwise empty lines is allowed provided that
      the amount of whitespace is identical to the indent in the
      previous line.
    </description>
    <internalKey>L001</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>L002</key>
    <name>Don't use tab characters</name>
    <description>
      Horizontal tabs are not consistently handled by editors and
      tools. Avoiding them ensures that the intended formatting of the
      code is preserved.
    </description>
    <internalKey>L002</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>L003</key>
    <name>No leading and no trailing empty lines</name>
    <description>
      Leading and trailing empty lines confuse users of various tools
      (like head and tail) and artificially influence some source code
      metrics.
    </description>
    <internalKey>L003</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>L004</key>
    <name>Line too long</name>
    <description>
      The source code line should not exceed some reasonable length.
    </description>
    <internalKey>L004</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>L005</key>
    <name>Too many consecutive empty lines</name>
    <description>
      The empty lines (if any) help to introduce more "light" in the
      source code, but they should not be overdosed in the sense that
      too many consecutive empty lines make the code harder to follow.
      Lines containing only whitespace are considered to be empty in
      this context.
    </description>
    <internalKey>L005</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>L006</key>
    <name>Source file is too long</name>
    <description>
      The source file should not exceed a reasonable length.
      Long source files can indicate an opportunity for refactoring.
    </description>
    <internalKey>L006</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T001</key>
    <name>One-line comments should not have forced continuation</name>
    <description>
      The one-line comment is a comment that starts with //.

      The usual intent is to let the comment continue till the end of
      the line, but the preprocessing rules of the language allow to
      actually continue the comment in the next line if line-splicing
      is forced with the backslash at the end of the line.

      But the line-splicing works only if the backslash is really the
      last character in the line - which is error prone because any
      white characters that might appear after the backslash will
      change the meaning of the program without being visible in the
      code.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T001</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T002</key>
    <name>Reserved name used for macro</name>
    <description>
      The C++ Standard reserves some forms of names for language
      implementations. One of the most frequent violations is a
      definition of preprocessor macro that begins with underscore
      followed by a capital letter or containing two consecutive
      underscores.

      Even though the majority of known compilers use more obscure
      names for internal purposes and the above code is not likely to
      cause any significant problems, all such names are formally
      reserved and therefore should not be used.

      Apart from the use of underscore in macro names, preprocessor
      macros should not be used to redefine language keywords.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T002</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T003</key>
    <name>Keyword not followed by a single space</name>
    <description>
      The keywords "case", "class", "delete", "enum", "explicit",
      "extern", "goto", "new", "struct", "union" and "using"
      should be followed by a single space for better readability.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T003</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T004</key>
    <name>Keyword not immediately followed by a colon</name>
    <description>
      The keywords "default", "private", "protected" and "public"
      should be immediately followed by a colon, unless used in the
      list of base classes.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T004</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T005</key>
    <name>Keyword not immediately followed by a semicolon</name>
    <description>
      The break and continue keywords should be immediately followed
      by a semicolon, with no other tokens in between.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T005</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T006</key>
    <name>Keyword not immediately followed by a semicolon or a single space</name>
    <description>
      The return and throw keywords should be immediately followed by
      a semicolon or a single space. An exception to this rule is
      allowed for exception specifications.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T006</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T007</key>
    <name>Semicolon is isolated from other tokens</name>
    <description>
      The semicolon should not stand isolated by whitespace or
      comments from the rest of the code. As an exception from this
      rule, semicolons surrounded by spaces are allowed in for loops:
    </description>
    <internalKey>T007</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T008</key>
    <name>Keyword not followed by a single space</name>
    <description>
      Keywords catch, for, if, switch and while should be followed by
      a single space and then an opening left parenthesis.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T008</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T009</key>
    <name>Wrong spacing around comma</name>
    <description>
      A comma, whether used as operator or in various lists, should
      not be preceded by whitespace on its left side, but should be
      followed by whitespace on its right side:
    </description>
    <internalKey>T009</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T010</key>
    <name>Identifiers should not be composed of only 'l' and 'O'</name>
    <description>
      The characters 'l' (which is lowercase 'L') and 'O' (which is
      uppercase 'o') should not be the only characters used in the
      identifier, because this would make them visually similar to
      numeric literals.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T010</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T011</key>
    <name>Opening/closing curly bracket mistake</name>
    <description>
      Corresponding curly brackets should be either in the same line
      or in the same column. This promotes clarity by emphasizing
      scopes, but allows concise style of one-line definitions and
      empty blocks.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T011</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T012</key>
    <name>Negation operator used in its short form</name>
    <description>
      The negation operator (exclamation mark) reduces readability of
      the code due to its terseness. Prefer explicit logical
      comparisons or alternative tokens for increased readability:
    </description>
    <internalKey>T012</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T013</key>
    <name>No copyright notice found</name>
    <description>
      The copyright notice is required by man coding standards and
      guidelines. In some countries every written artwork has some
      copyright, even if implicit. Prefer explicit notice to avoid any
      later confusion.
      This rule verifies that at least one comment in the source file
      contains the "copyright" word.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T013</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T014</key>
    <name>No reference to the Boost Software License found</name>
    <description>
      The Boost Software License should be referenced in the source
      code. This rule verifies that at least one comment in the
      source file contains the "Boost Software License" phrase. Note
      that this rule is very specific to the Boost libraries and those
      project that choose to use the Boost license. It is therefore
      not part of the default profile.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T014</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T015</key>
    <name>Incorrect HTML links</name>
    <description>
      The links embedded in comments and string literals should have
      correct form and should reference existing files.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T015</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T016</key>
    <internalKey>T016</internalKey>
    <name>Min/max potential macro substitution problem</name>
    <description>
      The calls to min and max functions should be protected against accidental macro substitution.
    </description>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T017</key>
    <name>Unnamed namespace not allowed in header file</name>
    <description>
      Unnamed namespaces are not allowed in header files.
      The typical use of unnamed namespace is to hide module-internal
      names from the outside world. Header files are physically
      concatenated in a single translation unit, which logically
      merges all namespaces with the same name. Unnamed namespaces are
      also merged in this process, which effectively undermines their
      initial purpose.
      Use named namespaces in header files. Unnamed namespaces are
      allowed in implementation files only.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T017</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T018</key>
    <name>Using namespace not allowed in header file</name>
    <description>
      Using namespace directives are not allowed in header files.

      The using namespace directive imports names from the given
      namespace and when used in a header file influences the global
      namespace of all the files that directly or indirectly include
      this header file.

      It is imaginable to use the using namespace directive in a
      limited scope in a header file (for example in a template or
      inline function definition), but for the sake of consistency
      this is also discouraged.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T018</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>T019</key>
    <name>Full block {} expected in the control structure</name>
    <description>
      Control structures managed by 'for', 'if' and 'while' constructs can
      be associated with a single instruction or with a complex block
      of code. Standardizing on the curly-braced blocks in all cases
      allows to avoid common pitfalls and makes the code visually more
      uniform.
    </description>
    <internalKey>T019</internalKey>
    <severity>INFO</severity>
    <type>CODE_SMELL</type>
    <remediationFunction>LINEAR</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>1min</remediationFunctionGapMultiplier>
  </rule>
</rules>
